ccmixter.org 2019-06-10

# ccMixter - CCMIXTER PRIVACY POLICY

## 1\. Introduction.

This Privacy Policy explains the collection, use, processing, transferring, and disclosure of personal information by ArtisTech Media (“ATM” or “ArtisTech”), a California Limited Liability Corporation.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and made part of ArtisTech Media Master Terms of Use (“Master Terms”) located at <http://ccmixter.org/terms>.

Unless otherwise noted on a particular website or service hosted by ArtisTech, this Privacy Policy applies to your use of all websites that ArtisTech operates. These include <http://ccmixter.org/>, <http://beta.ccmixter.org/>, <http://beta.ccmixter.org/pells>, <http://beta.ccmixter.org/stems>, <http://dig.ccmixter.org/>, <http://beta.ccmixter.org/playlists/browse>, and <http://tunetrack.net/>, together with all other subdomains thereof, (collectively, the “Websites”). This Privacy Policy also applies to all products, information, and services provided through the Websites, including without limitation the API and Login Services (defined below), (together with the Websites, the “Services”).

By accessing or using any of the Services, you are accepting and agreeing to the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

## 2\. Personal Information ATM Collects and How it is Used

As used in this policy, “personal information” means information that would allow someone to identify you, including your name, email address, IP address, or other information from which someone could deduce your identity.

ATM collects and uses personal information in the following ways:

**Website Analytics:** When you visit our Websites and use our Services, ATM collects some information about your activities through tools such as Google Analytics. The type of information that we collect focuses on general information such as country or city where you are located, pages visited, time spent on pages, heat-map of visitors’ activity on the site, information about the browser you are using, etc. ATM collects and uses this information pursuant to our legitimate interest in enhancing the security and utility of our Services. The information we gather and process is used in the aggregate to spot trends without deliberately identifying individuals.

Note that you can learn about Google’s practices in connection with its analytics services and how to opt out of it by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

ArtisTech also retains information about the usage of ccMixter, such as, for example, number of uploads, number of downloads, number of users. This information is aggregated and does not usually personally identify you, although limited personal information for some artists is displayed at <http://ccmixter.org/stats>. ArtisTech may make this aggregated information available to the public and other entities, such as our shareholders and advisors.

**Information from Cookies:** We and our service providers (for example, Google Analytics as described above) may collect information using cookies or similar technologies for the purposes described above and below. Cookies are pieces of information that are stored by your browser on the hard drive or memory of your computer or other Internet access device. Cookies may enable us to personalize your experience on the Services, maintain a persistent session, passively collect demographic information about your computer, and monitor other activities. The Websites may use different kinds of cookies and other types of local storage (such as browser-based or plugin-based local storage).

**Log-In Services:** When you register to obtain a user account on any of the Services (any such person, a “Registered User”), you will be asked to provide personal information to create your account and establish a password and profile. Through ccMixter, ArtisTech collects the personal information that you submit at the following pages: (a) account creation page, (b) artist profile page, (c) track upload page, and (d) discussion forums. You decide what and how much personal information we collect at these pages except that we require (through the ccMixter Terms) that your contact information is accurate and up-to-date in case we need to contact you for reasons related to ccMixter, for example, you have won a competition or have been selected to be on a remix event album, you’ve earned royalties, or someone claims music you posted to ccMixter is infringing or violates the terms of service . It is your responsibility to check and correct this information. All of the information you submit at the artist profile page (with the exception of your email address and password) and the discussion forums is made available at ccMixter to people who access ccMixter.

ArtisTech uses your email address and password solely for the purposes of: (a) administering ccMixter, so for example, to contact you about one of the tracks you uploaded or to send you a password reminder; and, (b) for the purpose of contacting you as part of a mass mailing about important changes to the ccMixter site. The first time we contact you as part of a mass mailing, we will give you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving future similar emails from us. 

ArtisTech also collects personal information about you when you send us an email or other communication. ArtisTech Media uses any such personal information solely for the purpose of responding to and acting appropriately in response to your email or other communication.

ATM collects and uses this personal information pursuant to its legitimate interest in establishing and maintaining your account providing you with the features we provide Registered Users. We may use your email address to contact you regarding changes to this policy or other applicable policies. The Login Name you provide in connection with your account may be used to attribute you in connection with any content you submit to any Service.

**Donations:** When you donate money to ArtisTech, you will be asked to provide personal information, including payment information. ATM collects and uses this personal information pursuant to its legitimate interest to process your donation.

**Other Voluntarily Provided Information:** When you provide feedback to ArtisTech, upload content, comment in the forums, or otherwise submit personal information, ATM collects and uses this personal information pursuant to its legitimate interest in better understanding our community of artists, supporters and volunteers and in furtherance of the activity about which you provided feedback or other input.

## 3\. Retention of Personal Information

The majority of the personal information collected and used as explained in Section 2 above is aggregated and stored in a central database hosted by a third party service provider. ATM aggregates this data pursuant to its legitimate interest in having information stored in a single location to minimize complexity, increase consistency in internal practices, better understand its community of artists, supporters and volunteers, and enhance the security of the data.

ATM erases the web browser logs described above on a regular, rolling basis. We generally retain other personal information for the purposes for which it was collected. This may mean that we retain your personal information indefinitely in some cases.

## 4\. Access to Your Personal Information

You are generally entitled to access and transfer to a third party any personal information that ArtisTech holds and to have inaccurate data corrected or removed to the extent ATM still maintains it. In certain circumstances, you also may have the right to object or restrict for legitimate reasons to the processing or transfer of personal information. If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please write to [info@artistechmedia.com](mailto:info@artistechmedia.com) explaining your request. You also have the right to go directly to the relevant supervisory or legal authority, but we encourage you to contact us so that we may resolve your concerns directly as best we can.

## 5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Information

ATM does not disclose personal information to third parties except as specified elsewhere in this policy and in the following instances:

  1. ArtisTech may share personal information with our contractors and service providers in order to undertake the activities described in Section 2.
  2. We may disclose your personal information to third parties in a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) take action regarding suspected illegal activities; (b) enforce or apply our Master Terms and this Privacy Policy, or (c) comply with legal process, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, or court order.

## 6\. Security of Your Personal Information

ArtisTech has implemented reasonable physical, technical, and organizational security measures for personal information that ATM processes against accidental or unlawful destruction, or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, in compliance with applicable law. However, no website can fully eliminate security risks. Third parties may circumvent our security measures to unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. If any data breach occurs, we will post a reasonably prominent notice to ccMixter and comply with all other applicable data privacy requirements including, when required, personal notice to you if you have provided and we have maintained an email address for you.

The ATM Login Services account systems have security risks in addition to those described above. Among other things, they are vulnerable to DNS attacks.

## 7\. Children

The Services are not directed at children under the age of 13. Consistent with the U.S. federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personal information from anyone under the age of 13 without requiring parental consent. Our Master Terms specifically prohibit anyone using our Services from submitting any personally identifiable information about persons under 13 years of age. Any person who provides their personal information to ATM through the Services represents that they are 13 years of age or older.

## 8\. Third Party Service Providers and Business Transfers

In general, it is not ArtisTech’'s practice to disclose personal information to third parties. We may share personal information in three instances.

  1. Firstly, ArtisTech uses third party service providers in connection with the Services, including but not limited to website hosting services, database management, and credit card processing. Some of these service providers may place session cookies on your computer, and they may collect and store your personal information on our behalf in accordance with the data practices and purposes explained above in Section 3. Additionally, ArtisTech may share personal information with our contractors and service providers in order to maintain, enhance, or add to the functionality of the site. In that case, ArtisTech requires those contractors and service providers to abide by this Privacy Policy and to only use any and all personal information solely for the purpose of performing their responsibilities for ArtisTech and then only to the extent necessary to perform those responsibilities.
  2. Secondly, we may share personal information with third parties such as the government or other entities when required to by law, in order to comply with section 512(g) of the US Copyright Act ([see…](http://tunetrack.net/dmca)), or as required by court order.
  3. Lastly, if ArtisTech transfer operations of ccMixter to another business or entity, or if ownership of all or substantially all or our business changes, or we undergo a corporate reorganization (including but not limited to a merger, consolidation or converting to a nonprofit corporation) or any other action or transfer (including but not limited to a transfer to Creative Commons or another entity or nonprofit corporation), you expressly consent to ArtisTech transferring your information to the new owner of the successor entity so that the Services and Websites can continue to be provided and operated, and you acknowledge customer, email and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions.

## 9\. Location of Services

If you are accessing or using the Services in regions with laws governing data collection, processing, transfer and use, please note that when we use and share your data as specified in this policy, we may transfer your information to recipients in countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information.

The Services are currently hosted in the United States, which means your personal information may be located on servers in the United States. This may change from time to time. The majority of contractors that ArtisTech is using as of the effective date of this Privacy Policy are located in the United States, but this may change from time to time.

## 10\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. When we do, we will provide you with notice of such update through (at a minimum) a reasonably prominent notice on ccMixter, including in the ccMixter.org Forums, and will revise the Effective Date below. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are protecting, using, processing and transferring the personal information we collect.

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [info@artistechmedia.com](mailto:info@artistechmedia.com).

**Effective Date:** November 8, 2018.

## Archived Versions of this Document

  * Terms pre 2018-12-29
